{
  "round": 1,
  "title": "Science & Technology",
  "type": "multiple_choice",
  "pass_on": false,
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "r1q1",
      "question": "What is the name of India’s first indigenously developed antibiotic targeting antimicrobial resistance (AMR)?",
      "options": ["Azithromycin", "Ciprofloxacin", "Nafithromycin", "Amoxicillin"],
      "answerIndex": 2,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q2",
      "question": "MeerKAT radio telescope, which was seen in the news, is located in which country?",
      "options": ["New Zealand", "South Africa", "Australia", "India"],
      "answerIndex": 1,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q3",
      "question": "Who among the following used the term computer worm for the first time?",
      "options": ["John Brunner", "Alan Turing", "John McCarthy", "JP Eckert"],
      "answerIndex": 0,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q4",
      "question": "The world’s largest solar tree in India has been developed by which institution?",
      "options": ["CSIR", "ISRO", "IISC", "IIT Bombay"],
      "answerIndex": 0,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q5",
      "question": "Which technology giant is going to set up a Center of Excellence for AI (Artificial Intelligence) along with GeM?",
      "options": ["Microsoft", "Infosys", "IBM", "Apple"],
      "answerIndex": 2,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q6",
      "question": "Name the 100th satellite that ISRO had launched from Sriharikota in Andhra Pradesh.",
      "options": ["GSAT-11", "RISAT-2", "Cartosat-2", "None of these"],
      "answerIndex": 2,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q7",
      "question": "What kind of light can accelerate the ageing process?",
      "options": ["Red light", "Blue light", "Yellow light", "Green light"],
      "answerIndex": 1,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q8",
      "question": "Which planet’s moon is Ganymede?",
      "options": ["Jupiter", "Saturn", "Venus", "Mercury"],
      "answerIndex": 0,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q9",
      "question": "“Bulletin”, a set of subscription and publishing tools, was launched by which social media company?",
      "options": ["Twitter", "Instagram", "Snapchat", "Facebook"],
      "answerIndex": 3,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "r1q10",
      "question": "Who is the founder of Oracle?",
      "options": ["Christ Lamb", "Larry Ellison", "James Carter", "Henry Smith"],
      "answerIndex": 1,
      "timeLimitSeconds": 20,
      "points": 10
    }
  ]
}
